Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
♪I drift across the boundless skies♪
♪أتجول عبر السماء اللامحدودة♪
♪Through deserts where no one goes♪
♪عبر الصحاري حيث لا أحد يذهب♪
♪Seeking myself♪
♪أبحث عن نفسي♪
♪The self I long to find♪
♪الذات التي أتوق للعثور عليها♪
♪Lost in a maze of lies♪
♪ضائع في متاهة من الأكاذيب♪
♪I break into your sea of clouds♪
♪أقتحم بحرك من السحب♪
♪It traps me♪
♪إنه يحاصرني♪
♪It redeems me♪
♪إنه يخلصني♪
♪Which hue of the sky is your love?♪
♪ما هو لون السماء الذي يحبك؟♪
♪Or is it the burning flame♪
♪ أم أنها الشعلة المشتعلة ♪
♪Found only in storms?♪
♪توجد فقط في العواصف؟♪
♪You are the mark engraved upon my heart♪
♪أنت العلامة المحفورة على قلبي♪
♪From then on all my memories tremble for you♪
♪ومنذ ذلك الحين، كل ذكرياتي ترتجف من أجلك♪
♪What I cannot forget is that fleeting gaze♪
♪ما لا أستطيع أن أنساه هو تلك النظرة العابرة♪
♪What I cannot escape is passion born in chaos♪
♪ما لا أستطيع الهروب منه هو العاطفة المولودة في الفوضى♪
♪How I long to hold you again♪
♪كم أتوق إلى احتضانك مرة أخرى♪
♪Our love, high among the clouds♪
♪حبنا، عالياً بين السحاب♪
♪Is sealed with that kiss♪
♪مختوم بتلك القبلة♪
[Love in The Clouds]
[الحب في السحاب]
[Adapted from Bai Lu Cheng Shuang's "Love in The Clouds"]
[مقتبس من رواية "الحب في السحاب" لباي لو تشنغ شوانغ]
Situ Ling let you out of the Sunken Abyss.
سيتيو لينغ يسمح لك بالخروج من الهاوية الغارقة.
Then Lord Hanfeng had me
ثم كان اللورد هانفينج هو من جعلني
go through all that trouble
تجاوز كل هذه المتاعب
to capture you one by one.
لالتقاطكم واحدا تلو الآخر.
It took so long
لقد استغرق الأمر وقتا طويلا
and so much Blessed Rain
والكثير من المطر المبارك
to fatten you up nicely.
لتسمينك بشكل جيد.
How could I let you go now?
كيف يمكنني أن أتركك الآن؟
We are surrounded by powerful enemies.
نحن محاطون بأعداء أقوياء.
We can't keep Ji Bozai under control,
لا يمكننا إبقاء جي بوزاي تحت السيطرة،
so we must offer you
لذلك يجب علينا أن نقدم لك
to the netherbeasts as soon as possible
إلى الوحوش السفلية في أقرب وقت ممكن
to help them grow into an army.
لمساعدتهم على النمو ليصبحوا جيشًا.
Sir,
سيد،
please let us go!
من فضلك دعونا نذهب!
Please spare us!
من فضلك انقذنا!
Have mercy on us, sir!
ارحمنا يا سيدي!
Aren't you afraid?
ألا تخافين؟
Of you?
منك؟
[Episode 15]
[الحلقة 15]
Do you really think this act of yours will work?
هل تعتقد حقا أن هذا التصرف الخاص بك سوف ينجح؟
The more unpredictable our moves,
كلما أصبحت تحركاتنا غير متوقعة،
the more likely we are to confuse others.
كلما زادت احتمالية إرباك الآخرين، كلما زاد احتمال إرباكنا للآخرين.
So you mean
فهل تقصد
Ji Bozai's sudden visit
زيارة جي بوزاي المفاجئة
must have alerted Mu Qibai,
لا بد أن يكون قد نبه مو تشيباي،
and for his own safety,
ولأجل سلامته،
he likely sent most of his men,
من المرجح أنه أرسل معظم رجاله،
if not all, to Moonlit Blossoms.
إن لم يكن كلها، إلى أزهار القمر.
It's uncertain if our plan will work,
من غير المؤكد ما إذا كانت خطتنا ستنجح،
but it's worth a try.
لكن الأمر يستحق المحاولة.
If their defenses have weakened,
إذا ضعفت دفاعاتهم،
we have a chance
لدينا فرصة
at finding the method Xinliu mentioned for breeding netherbeasts.
عند العثور على الطريقة التي ذكرها شينليو لتربية الوحوش السفلية.
Right.
يمين.
I'll be back soon.
سأعود قريبا.
This time, I'll find out what that old fox's been hiding!
هذه المرة سأكتشف ما كان يخفيه هذا الثعلب العجوز!
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
the ledger Mu Qibai keeps,
الدفتر الذي يحتفظ به مو تشيباي،
the one recording the dealings of Heavenly Grief,
الذي يسجل تعاملات الحزن السماوي،
is probably at Dragon Carp Terrace too.
ربما يكون موجودًا في Dragon Carp Terrace أيضًا.
I'll sneak in and look for it.
سأتسلل وأبحث عنه.
Be careful this time.
كن حذرا هذه المرة.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Where did Mu Qibai hide it?
أين أخفاه مو تشيباي؟
Why is this room so hot?
لماذا هذه الغرفة حارة جداً؟
You never learn, do you?
أنت لا تتعلم أبدًا، أليس كذلك؟
We meet again, Kitten.
لقد التقينا مرة أخرى، يا قطتي.
Relax.
يستريح.
This time, I won't pretend
هذه المرة لن أتظاهر
to let you escape.
لأسمح لك بالهروب.
I'll just kill you.
سأقتلك فقط.
I knew you were behind this.
لقد عرفت أنك كنت وراء هذا.
Kitten,
هريرة،
you've got sharp claws.
لديك مخالب حادة.
Messing with you is always such fun.
اللعب معك هو دائما متعة.
It's quite fun to mess with you too.
من الممتع جدًا العبث معك أيضًا.
You brought backup this time?
هل احضرت نسخة احتياطية هذه المرة؟
[Granny's Eatery]
[مطعم الجدة]
Scallion,
البصل الأخضر،
it's ready.
إنه جاهز.
Take it to that table.
خذها إلى تلك الطاولة.
Wheat,
قمح،
bring this one over too.
أحضر هذا أيضًا.
You weren't even surprised to see me in human form.
لم تكن متفاجئًا حتى لرؤيتي في شكل بشري.
You and your lord
أنت وربك
must know quite a lot.
يجب أن أعرف الكثير.
Ji Bozai may not have reached the Perfected Stage yet,
ربما لم يصل جي بوزاي إلى المرحلة المثالية بعد،
but he's long attained the Transcendent Stage,
ولكنه وصل منذ فترة طويلة إلى المرحلة السامية،
so it's not surprising that he has
لذلك ليس من المستغرب أن يكون لديه
a shapeshifting companion beast.
وحش رفيق متغير الشكل.
Besides, Ji Bozai still doesn't fully trust
بالإضافة إلى ذلك، لا يزال جي بوزاي لا يثق بشكل كامل
Ming Yi or me,
مينغ يي أو أنا،
so I knew he'd
لذلك كنت أعلم أنه
send you to keep an eye on me.
أرسلك لمراقبتي.
Scallion pancakes with dried fish.
فطائر البصل الأخضر مع السمك المجفف.
My first time making them.
هذه أول مرة أقوم بصنعها.
I'm not sure how it tastes.
أنا لست متأكدًا من طعمه.
Please, enjoy.
من فضلك استمتع.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
You, a dragon,
أنت، تنين،
are openly walking around the market.
يتجولون علانية في السوق.
Are you sure that's fine?
هل أنت متأكد من أن هذا جيد؟
His Lordship has...
لقد قام سيادته ...
Please, enjoy.
من فضلك استمتع.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
His Lordship has already gone head-to-head with them.
لقد دخل سيادته بالفعل في مواجهة معهم وجهاً لوجه.
I don't need to stay hidden anymore.
لا أحتاج إلى البقاء مختبئًا بعد الآن.
That's true.
هذا صحيح.
Do you want some fish?
هل تريد بعض السمك؟
You dragons all eat fish, right?
أنتم التنانين تأكلون السمك، أليس كذلك؟
I have a name.
عندي اسم.
Eat. Then go back.
كُل. ثم عد.
You won't even tell me your name.
لن تخبرني حتى باسمك.
Please enjoy.
من فضلك استمتع.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
It's Buxiu.
انها بوكسيو.
I'm Twenty-Seven.
عمري سبعة وعشرون عامًا.
Buxiu.
بوكسيو.
That's a good name.
هذا اسم جيد.
Honestly,
بصدق،
I kind of envy you dragons.
أنا أحسدكم نوعا ما أيها التنانين.
You are big and majestic.
أنت كبير ومهيب.
And when you take human form,
وعندما تأخذ شكل الإنسان،
you're pretty well built too.
لقد بنيت بشكل جيد أيضًا.
You're leaving already?
هل أنت تغادر بالفعل؟
Wait for me!
الانتظار لي!
[Benevolence, Kindness, Wisdom, and Propriety]
[الإحسان، واللطف، والحكمة، واللياقة]
Yuanfeng,
يوانفينج،
isn't it funny?
أليس هذا مضحكا؟
That Ji Bozai
ذلك جي بوزاي
actually came to negotiate peace with me.
لقد جاء فعلا للتفاوض على السلام معي.
We talked all night.
لقد تحدثنا طوال الليل.
Clearly, he was
من الواضح أنه كان
trying to distract me.
محاولة تشتيت انتباهي.
Luckily, I sent men
لحسن الحظ، لقد أرسلت رجالاً
to guard Dragon Carp Terrace.
لحراسة تراس دراجون كارب.
Lord Hanfeng, he...
اللورد هانفينج، هو...
Get lost.
اغرب عن وجهي.
Yes, My Lord.
نعم سيدي.
Yuanfeng, you're asleep
يوانفينج، أنت نائم.
and unaware of what's happening outside.
وغير مدركين لما يحدث في الخارج.
I once admired Ji Bozai's talent
لقد أعجبت بموهبة جي بوزاي ذات مرة
and wanted him
وأراده
to serve Jixing Abyss.
لخدمة Jixing Abyss.
Who would have thought he'd only want to stand against me?
من كان يظن أنه يريد الوقوف ضدي فقط؟
Yuanfeng,
يوانفينج،
he understands nothing.
إنه لا يفهم شيئا.
Winning a single Qingyun Tournament for Jixing Abyss
الفوز ببطولة تشينغيون واحدة لجيشينغ أبيس
means nothing.
لا يعني شيئا.
Only by raising
فقط عن طريق رفع
the netherbeasts into an army
الوحوش السفلية في جيش
and harnessing their power
وتسخير قوتهم
will Jixing Abyss truly fear no one.
هل حقا لن يخاف جيكسينج أبيس من أحد؟
Yuanfeng,
يوانفينج،
for Jixing Abyss to grow strong,
لكي تنمو Jixing Abyss بقوة،
some sacrifices
بعض التضحيات
must be made.
يجب أن يتم ذلك.
I failed in my duty.
لقد فشلت في أداء واجبي.
The intruder escaped.
لقد هرب المتسلل.
What did you just say?
ماذا قلت للتو؟
I...
أنا...
I failed in my duty.
لقد فشلت في أداء واجبي.
The intruder...
الدخيل...
Ji Bozai was too cunning.
لقد كان جي بوزاي ماكرًا جدًا.
He had a backup plan
لقد كان لديه خطة احتياطية
and sent someone to help.
وأرسل شخصًا للمساعدة.
That person carried the same aura as he.
كان هذا الشخص يحمل نفس الهالة التي كان يحملها.
I suspect
انا اشتبه
it was his companion beast.
لقد كان رفيقه الوحشي.
It's likely
من المرجح
Ji Bozai has concealed
لقد أخفى جي بوزاي
his true cultivation stage,
مرحلة زراعته الحقيقية،
and his companion beast has already learned to take human form.
ورفيقه الوحشي تعلم بالفعل كيفية اتخاذ الشكل البشري.
They didn't find anything else, did they?
ولم يجدوا شيئا آخر، أليس كذلك؟
No.
لا.
I swear, Lord Hanfeng,
أقسم يا سيد هانفينج،
I didn't give away the existence of the Soul-Consuming Tree!
لم أكشف عن وجود شجرة استهلاك الروح!
I failed in my duty.
لقد فشلت في أداء واجبي.
After arguing
بعد الجدال
with Ming Yi,
مع مينغ يي،
Ji Bozai was thrown out
تم طرد جي بوزاي
and stayed the night at Moonlit Blossoms.
وأقمت الليل في Moonlit Blossoms.
So we monitored Shouhua Academy as ordered,
لذا قمنا بمراقبة أكاديمية شوهوا كما هو مطلوب،
watching Ming Yi all night.
مشاهدة مينغ يي طوال الليل.
But unexpectedly,
ولكن بشكل غير متوقع،
Ji Bozai
جي بوزاي
somehow made Ming Xian's white cat obey him,
بطريقة ما، تمكن من جعل قطة مينغ شيان البيضاء تطيعه،
and together with his companion beast, the cat...
ومع رفيقه الوحش القط...
Yan Xiao!
يان شياو!
During your days of training at Shouhua Academy,
خلال أيام تدريبك في أكاديمية شوهوا،
you really played the dutiful physician well,
لقد لعبت دور الطبيب المخلص بشكل جيد حقًا،
working in perfect sync with Ji Bozai.
العمل في مزامنة مثالية مع جي بوزاي.
I saw it every day,
لقد رأيته كل يوم،
and I couldn't help but wonder
ولم أستطع إلا أن أتساءل
if you were...
لو كنت...
I only wanted
انا فقط اردت
to avoid worsening my relationship with Ji Bozai.
لتجنب تدهور علاقتي مع جي بوزاي.
Otherwise, it would've been even harder to get things done.
وإلا لكان إنجاز الأمور أصعب.
I have no ulterior motives.
ليس لدي أي دوافع خفية.
I ask for your discernment, Lord Hanfeng.
أطلب منك التمييز، يا سيد هانفينج.
Me too.
أنا أيضاً.
I've spent so much effort on it,
لقد بذلت الكثير من الجهد عليه،
but it seems this useless thing will never grow tall.
لكن يبدو أن هذا الشيء عديم الفائدة لن ينمو أبدًا.
I should pull it out.
ينبغي لي أن أخرجه.
I know of a folk remedy
أنا أعرف علاجًا شعبيًا
that might help this Hanqing Bamboo.
قد يساعد هذا الخيزران هانكينج.
You can heal plants too?
هل يمكنك شفاء النباتات أيضًا؟
I will fetch the materials right away.
سأحضر المواد على الفور.
Fetch the materials?
احضار المواد؟
If I remember correctly,
إذا كنت أتذكر بشكل صحيح،
the key ingredient
المكون الرئيسي
in that remedy is teeth, isn't it?
في هذا العلاج الأسنان، أليس كذلك؟
Yes.
نعم.
Teeth...
أسنان...
ground into powder.
مطحون إلى مسحوق.
I never said
لم اقل ابدا
I wanted your teeth.
أردت أسنانك.
I'll do it myself.
سأفعل ذلك بنفسي.
You are truly skilled in medicine.
أنت ماهر حقا في الطب.
You even cured Sun Liao's foul mouth.
لقد قمت حتى بعلاج فم سون لياو القذر.
Now, about caring for my brother,
الآن، فيما يتعلق برعاية أخي،
nothing will go wrong, right?
لن يحدث أي خطأ، أليس كذلك؟
I will do my utmost, Your Lordship.
سأبذل قصارى جهدي، يا صاحب السعادة.
That tree is definitely more than it seems.
هذه الشجرة بالتأكيد أكثر مما تبدو عليه.
Mu Qibai loves plants,
مو تشيباي يحب النباتات،
but in his entire courtyard,
ولكن في فناءه بأكمله،
only that tree is thriving.
فقط تلك الشجرة هي المزدهرة.
It's as if it's draining all the others
إنه كما لو أنه يستنزف كل الآخرين
to feed itself.
لتغذية نفسها.
The one I saw in Hou Zhao's memories
الذي رأيته في ذكريات هو تشاو
must have been that tree.
لا بد أن تكون تلك الشجرة.
It likely extends from the courtyard
من المرجح أن يمتد من الفناء
into a hidden chamber underground.
إلى غرفة مخفية تحت الأرض.
Its roots looked demonic.
جذورها تبدو شيطانية.
If it can drain other trees,
إذا كان بإمكانه تجفيف الأشجار الأخرى،
it might
ربما
also consume primordial spirits.
كما تستهلك أيضًا الأرواح البدائية.
I once read
لقد قرأت مرة
about an ancient technique from the Mangfu Swamp.
حول تقنية قديمة من مستنقع مانجفو.
It allows one to extract a person's primordial spirit
فهو يسمح للمرء باستخراج الروح البدائية للشخص
and bind it to a towering tree,
وربطها بشجرة شاهقة،
turning the tree into a Soul-Consuming Tree.
تحويل الشجرة إلى شجرة مستهلكة للروح.
The air around it reeks of blood.
الهواء حولها مليء برائحة الدم.
Such trees can preserve primordial spirits
يمكن لهذه الأشجار أن تحافظ على الأرواح البدائية
until someone uses them.
حتى يستخدمها شخص ما.
Could this be the same method Xinliu mentioned
هل يمكن أن تكون هذه هي نفس الطريقة التي ذكرها شينليو؟
for breeding netherbeasts?
لتربية الوحوش السفلية؟
The best nourishment for a netherbeast
أفضل غذاء للوحش السفلي
is the primordial spirit of a living being.
هي الروح البدائية للكائن الحي.
A century ago, netherbeasts ravaged the realms,
منذ قرن من الزمان، اجتاح الوحوش السفلية العوالم،
devouring everyone in their path.
التهام كل من في طريقه.
Even the Spiritual Veins Fairies who raised them
حتى جنيات الأوردة الروحية التي ربتهم
were eaten alive.
تم أكلهم أحياء.
If Mu Qibai
إذا مو تشيباي
gathers these beasts into an army,
يجمع هذه الوحوش في جيش،
there will be disastrous consequences.
ستكون هناك عواقب وخيمة.
This is serious.
هذا أمر خطير.
We should report it to the Emperor of Jixing.
ينبغي لنا أن نبلغ إمبراطور جيشينغ بذلك.
The Emperor has long been under Mu Qibai's control,
لقد كان الإمبراطور تحت سيطرة مو تشي باي لفترة طويلة،
trapped in slumber for years.
عالقًا في النوم لسنوات.
He's no different from a puppet.
إنه لا يختلف عن الدمية.
Then maybe we should alert the other five realms.
ثم ربما يجب علينا تنبيه العوالم الخمسة الأخرى.
Those in power
أولئك في السلطة
are all the same.
كلها متشابهة.
If they learn
إذا تعلموا
of a netherbeast army,
من جيش الوحوش السفلية،
they'll only want to claim it for themselves
إنهم يريدون فقط المطالبة بها لأنفسهم
and use it to dominate the Six Realms.
واستخدمها للسيطرة على العوالم الستة.
Not all who hold power
ليس كل من يملك السلطة
are slaves to it.
عبيد لها.
Some still care
لا يزال البعض يهتم
for the lives of others.
من أجل حياة الآخرين.
We should try to unite as many as we can.
ينبغي علينا أن نحاول توحيد أكبر عدد ممكن من الناس.
Unite?
توحد؟
That's impossible.
هذا مستحيل.
But we're too few in number.
لكن عددنا قليل جدًا.
Those netherbeasts are far too strong.
تلك الوحوش السفلية قوية جدًا.
If we fail
إذا فشلنا
to stop Mu Qibai,
لإيقاف مو تشيباي،
what will happen to the Six Realms?
ماذا سيحدث للعوالم الستة؟
You grew up safely in Yaoguang Palace,
لقد نشأت بأمان في قصر ياوجوانج،
receiving support from the Lower Realms for seven years.
تلقي الدعم من العوالم السفلية لمدة سبع سنوات.
Naturally, you believe there are still
بطبيعة الحال، أنت تعتقد أنه لا يزال هناك
righteous people in the Six Realms.
الناس الصالحين في العوالم الستة.
If you had spent even a single day in the Sunken Abyss,
لو قضيت يومًا واحدًا في الهاوية الغارقة،
you would understand
سوف تفهم
how greedy and malicious people can be.
كيف يمكن للناس أن يكونوا جشعين وخبيثين.
If the netherbeast army is ever exposed,
إذا تم الكشف عن جيش الوحوش السفلية،
before Mu Qibai even stirs up trouble,
قبل أن يثير مو تشيباي المتاعب،
the Six Realms will all fall into chaos over that power,
ستقع العوالم الستة كلها في حالة من الفوضى بسبب تلك القوة،
and Yaoguang Mountain will be no exception.
ولن يكون جبل ياوجوانج استثناءً.
The fact
الحقيقة
that you take no pride in your background
أنك لا تفتخر بخلفيتك
is already rare enough.
إنه أمر نادر بالفعل.
So just being born in an Upper Realm
لذا، مجرد ولادتي في عالم أعلى
is already considered rare.
ويعتبر نادرًا بالفعل.
Tianji has issued a decree.
أصدرت تيانجي مرسومًا.
Starting today, the training is over.
ابتداءً من اليوم، انتهى التدريب.
You no longer need to stay at Shouhua Academy.
لم تعد هناك حاجة للبقاء في أكاديمية شوهوا.
Head back now.
العودة الآن.
I don't want this companion beast
لا أريد هذا الرفيق الوحشي
to get into any more trouble while in my care.
الوقوع في أي مشكلة أخرى أثناء وجودي تحت رعايتي.
[Zhushui Spiritual State]
[حالة تشوشوي الروحية]
Greetings, Father.
تحياتي لك يا أبي.
Chao Yu,
تشاو يو,
you've done well quelling the rebellion
لقد نجحت في قمع التمرد
in Cangwu Hill.
في تل كانجوو.
Is there any reward you wish for?
هل هناك أي مكافأة تتمنى الحصول عليها؟
[Chao Yu, First Prince of Zhushui] It was only my duty. I wish for nothing.
[تشاو يو، أول أمير لتشوشوي] كان هذا واجبي فقط. لا أتمنى شيئًا.
You deserve a reward.
أنت تستحق المكافأة.
How about I grant you the title of Lord Jingxi?
ماذا عن منحك لقب اللورد جينغشي؟
That would be a great honor, Father.
سيكون هذا شرفًا عظيمًا، يا أبي.
But truly,
ولكن حقا،
all I wish is to help you...
كل ما أتمناه هو مساعدتك...
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
rumors have been spreading through the Judgment Hall
انتشرت الشائعات في قاعة الحكم
and the Medical Hall
والقاعة الطبية
[Chao Heng, Emperor of Zhushui] that I intend to name you Crown Prince.
[تشاو هينج، إمبراطور تشوشوي] أنني أنوي أن أطلق عليك لقب ولي العهد.
Have you heard such talk?
هل سمعت مثل هذا الحديث؟
Let me show you something.
دعني أريك شيئا.
The tongues of those who spread the rumors are all inside.
ألسنة الذين ينشرون الشائعات كلها في الداخل.
They... they brought this upon themselves.
لقد جلبوا هذا على أنفسهم.
I'll ask you again.
سأسألك مرة أخرى.
You deserve a reward.
أنت تستحق المكافأة.
How about I grant you the title of Lord Jingxi?
ماذا عن منحك لقب اللورد جينغشي؟
Father, please believe me.
أبي، من فضلك صدقني.
I live only to serve and support you.
أنا أعيش فقط لخدمتك ودعمك.
I have no ulterior ambitions.
ليس لدي أي طموحات خفية.
Please believe me, Father!
أرجوك أن تصدقني يا أبي!
Congratulations, My Lord,
مبروك يا سيدي
on receiving the title of Lord Jingxi.
عند حصوله على لقب اللورد جينغشي.
Get lost!
اغرب عن وجهي!
Forgive me, My Lord.
اغفر لي يا ربي.
I thought you had
اعتقدت أنك قد
the Crown Prince's seat in the bag this time.
مقعد ولي العهد في الحقيبة هذه المرة.
But I just heard
ولكنني سمعت للتو
that Father only gave you the title of Lord Jingxi
هذا الأب أعطاك لقب اللورد جينغشي فقط
and even killed a few of your men.
وحتى قتل بعضًا من رجالك.
Did you come here to mock me?
هل أتيت إلى هنا للسخرية مني؟
I wouldn't dare.
لا أجرؤ على ذلك.
Father hasn't named a Crown Prince yet
لم يسمي الأب وليًا للعهد بعد
because he has many sons
لأنه لديه العديد من الأبناء
and wants to see who proves himself best.
ويريد أن يرى من يثبت نفسه بشكل أفضل.
But I truly hope
ولكنني آمل حقا
[Chao Xuan, Second Prince of Zhushui] you'll be the one named Crown Prince.
[تشاو شوان، الأمير الثاني لتشوشوي] أنت ستكون الشخص الذي يُدعى ولي العهد.
What are you getting at?
ماذا تقصد؟
Do you know
هل تعلم
where Chao Yuan has been these past few months?
أين كان تشاو يوان في الأشهر القليلة الماضية؟
That good-for-nothing?
هذا الذي لا يصلح لشيء؟
Where else could he go?
أين يمكنه أن يذهب؟
He heard
لقد سمع
Jixing Abyss was refining medicine in the Sunken Abyss
كان جيكسينج أبيس يقوم بتكرير الأدوية في الهاوية الغارقة
and went to seek the Golden Millet Dream.
وذهب للبحث عن حلم الدخن الذهبي.
What?
ماذا؟
Yu, you were always kind to Chao Yuan growing up.
يو، لقد كنت دائمًا لطيفًا مع تشاو يوان أثناء نشأتك.
But if he finds the Golden Millet Dream first
ولكن إذا وجد حلم الدخن الذهبي أولاً
and brings it to Father,
ويحضره إلى الأب،
do you think
هل تعتقد
Father will allow him to cultivate spiritual veins?
هل يسمح له الأب بتنمية الأوردة الروحية؟
That will be a great accomplishment.
سيكون هذا إنجازًا عظيمًا.
Do you think it will earn him
هل تعتقد أنه سوف يكسبه؟
a chance at the Crown Prince's seat?
فرصة للحصول على مقعد ولي العهد؟
What?
ماذا؟
That great man is coming to Jixing Abyss in person?
هل سيأتي ذلك الرجل العظيم إلى هاوية جيكسينج شخصيًا؟
Yes.
نعم.
But since he's a warrior,
ولكن لأنه محارب،
he cannot enter the realm.
لا يستطيع دخول العالم.
He specifically asked that Your Lordship go out to greet him
لقد طلب من سيادتكم على وجه التحديد الخروج لاستقباله
and escort him.
ورافقه.
Your Lordship.
سيادتكم.
After all these days,
بعد كل هذه الأيام،
Mu Qibai has finally left Dragon Carp Terrace.
لقد غادر مو تشيباي أخيرًا تراس دراغون كارب.
Yes.
نعم.
He prepared a ship and a carriage.
قام بإعداد سفينة وعربة.
It seems he's going on a long journey.
يبدو أنه ذاهب في رحلة طويلة.
I placed the Tracking Seal Ming Yi made
لقد وضعت ختم التتبع الذي صنعه مينغ يي
on his vehicles.
على مركباته.
For the next 12 hours,
خلال الـ 12 ساعة القادمة،
we'll be able to track his movements.
سوف نكون قادرين على تتبع تحركاته.
Those little trinkets she's made
تلك الحلي الصغيرة التي صنعتها
really do come in handy.
إنها مفيدة حقا.
Indeed.
بالفعل.
Earlier, as per your order,
في وقت سابق، وفقا لطلبك،
I observed Twenty-Seven
لقد لاحظت سبعة وعشرين
near Dragon Carp Terrace.
بالقرب من تراس دراغون كارب.
He was thorough in his search,
لقد كان دقيقا في بحثه،
and I found nothing suspicious.
ولم أجد شيئا مثيرا للريبة.
As Ming Xian's companion beast,
كوحش رفيق لمينغ شيان،
he's obedient to Ming Yi
إنه مطيع لمينغ يي
probably because she shares a strong bond
ربما لأنها تشترك في رابطة قوية
with Ming Xian.
مع مينغ شيان.
Let's set off.
دعونا ننطلق.
Immortal Ji.
الناس الخالدون.
You've already formed a heart imprint with Ji Bozai.
لقد قمت بالفعل بتكوين بصمة قلب مع جي بوزاي.
Now hurry and see him off
الآن اسرع وودعه
so we can head to his Spirit Well.
حتى نتمكن من التوجه إلى بئر روحه.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
You're worried I might covet the netherbeast army?
هل أنت قلق من أنني قد أطمع في جيش الوحوش السفلية؟
If you are, come with me.
إذا كنت كذلك، تعال معي.
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
I believe you are just like me.
أعتقد أنك مثلي تمامًا.
You won't be tempted by this dangerous power.
لن تغريك هذه القوة الخطيرة.
It will be cold tonight,
سيكون الجو باردًا الليلة
and your journey will be perilous.
وستكون رحلتك محفوفة بالمخاطر.
Please take care of yourself.
من فضلك اعتني بنفسك .
Would you let him go alone in search of the netherbeasts too?
هل ستتركه يذهب بمفرده للبحث عن الوحوش السفلية أيضًا؟
I mean,
أعني،
the power of a netherbeast army
قوة جيش الوحوش السفلية
is tempting to everyone, isn't it?
إنه أمر مغر للجميع، أليس كذلك؟
Right now, aside from myself,
في الوقت الحالي، بجانب نفسي،
the only person I trust is you, Immortal Ji.
الشخص الوحيد الذي أثق به هو أنت، جي الخالد.
Though he's gone, there's still someone watching me.
رغم رحيله، لا زال هناك من يراقبني.
Granny Xun,
الجدة شون،
did Lord Ji tell you to keep an eye on me?
هل قال لك اللورد جي أن تراقبني؟
Here, have some Blessing Cakes.
تفضلوا، تناولوا بعض كعكات البركة.
I'll just
انا فقط سأفعل
sit right here.
اجلس هنا.
I'm not going anywhere.
انا لا اذهب الى اي مكان.
Watch me all you want.
شاهدني كما تريد.
Go on. Try one.
إستمر، جرب واحدة.
I'm not eating those.
انا لا آكل تلك.
What exactly is your relationship with Ming Xian?
ما هي علاقتك مع مينغ شيان بالضبط؟
Since His Lordship spared you,
لأن سيادته قد أنقذك،
you probably aren't a real threat.
ربما أنك لا تشكل تهديدًا حقيقيًا.
But I still have to ask...
ولكن لا يزال يتعين علي أن أسأل...
I was engaged to Ming Xian.
لقد كنت مخطوبة لمينغ شيان.
Engaged?
مرتبط؟
To Ming Xian?
إلى مينغ شيان؟
So you're a spy from Yaoguang Mountain.
إذن أنت جاسوس من جبل ياوجوانج.
No, that can't be,
لا، هذا لا يمكن أن يكون،
or Lord Ji would never have spared you.
أو أن اللورد جي لم يكن ليوفر لك ذلك أبدًا.
Since he kept you around,
منذ أن أبقى معك،
you must mean him no harm.
لا بد أنك لا تقصد له أي أذى.
But how did you end up in Jixing Abyss,
ولكن كيف انتهى بك الأمر في Jixing Abyss،
in Moonlit Blossoms?
في زهور القمر؟
- I... - Was that Ming Xian
- أنا... - هل كان هذا مينغ شيان
as shameless as my old man who beat me
وقح مثل والدي الذي ضربني
every day?
كل يوم؟
Did he send you to Moonlit Blossoms to make ends meet?
هل أرسلك إلى Moonlit Blossoms لتغطية نفقاتك؟
In a way, yes.
بطريقة ما، نعم.
To think that a Warrior God
أن نفكر في أن إله المحارب
could stoop that low!
يمكن أن ينحدر إلى هذا المستوى!
Listen,
يستمع،
His Lordship won't really hold that against you.
لن يحمل سيادته هذا الأمر ضدك حقًا.
He once helped me,
لقد ساعدني ذات مرة،
and I'm sure he's willing to help you too.
وأنا متأكد من أنه على استعداد لمساعدتك أيضًا.
But you really shouldn't have kept secrets from him.
ولكنك حقًا لم يكن ينبغي أن تخفي عنه أي أسرار.
You really went too far.
لقد ذهبت بعيدا جدا حقا.
Let me tell you...
دعني أخبرك...
Granny Xun?
الجدة شون؟
Ming Yi!
مينغ يي!
I've read about the Sunken Abyss.
لقد قرأت عن الهاوية الغارقة.
It looks exactly like this.
يبدو تماما مثل هذا.
Ji Bozai's Spirit Well resembles
يشبه بئر روح جي بوزاي
the Sunken Abyss so much.
الهاوية الغارقة كثيرا.
He's no longer a prisoner,
لم يعد سجينا
yet he's still trapped here.
ولكنه لا يزال محاصرا هنا.
The Golden Millet Dream is here.
حلم الدخن الذهبي هنا.
The Golden Millet Dream?
حلم الدخن الذهبي؟
A blood seal.
ختم الدم.
Ji Bozai formed a heart imprint with me,
لقد شكّل جي بوزاي بصمة قلب معي،
so he added this seal
فأضاف هذا الختم
to keep me from taking it.
لمنعني من أخذه.
Let us go, please!
دعنا نذهب من فضلك!
Please spare us!
من فضلك انقذنا!
Have mercy on us!
ارحمنا!
Let us go, please!
دعنا نذهب من فضلك!
Please spare us!
من فضلك انقذنا!
- These... - Please let us go!
- هؤلاء... - من فضلك دعونا نذهب!
are the spirits of the Sunken Abyss prisoners!
هم أرواح سجناء الهاوية الغارقة!
Please spare us, sir!
أرجوك أن تنقذنا يا سيدي!
Please let us go!
من فضلك دعونا نذهب!
Weren't those innocents
ألم يكن هؤلاء الأبرياء
already released?
تم إصداره بالفعل؟
I don't want to die yet.
لا أريد أن أموت بعد.
They didn't get out of the Sunken Abyss safely.
لم يتمكنوا من الخروج من الهاوية الغارقة بأمان.
Sir, spare us. Please, I'm begging you!
سيدي، أنقذنا. أرجوك، أنا أتوسل إليك!
Mu Qibai had them captured again.
تمكن مو تشيباي من القبض عليهم مرة أخرى.
- Please let us go! - Have mercy on us!
- من فضلك دعنا نذهب! - ارحمنا!
Please let me go.
من فضلك دعني أذهب.
Now,
الآن،
their primordial spirits have been stripped away.
لقد تم تجريدهم من أرواحهم البدائية.
They died here,
لقد ماتوا هنا
never to be reborn.
لن تولد من جديد أبدًا.
We're all innocent.
نحن جميعا أبرياء.
I really am innocent.
أنا بريء حقا.
I did nothing wrong!
لم أفعل شيئا خاطئا!
Please let me go!
من فضلك دعني أذهب!
Afraid of you?
خائف منك؟
I even recovered from my Withered-Branch Disease.
حتى أنني تعافيت من مرض الأغصان الذابل.
I'll live on
سأعيش
and grow
وتنمو
into a towering tree.
إلى شجرة شاهقة.
Sir, my child is still young.
سيدي، طفلي لا يزال صغيرا.
Please, spare us.
من فضلك، انقذنا.
Impossible.
مستحيل.
Why is Fairy Ruo Shui here?
لماذا الجنية رو شوي هنا؟
Didn't we already...?
ألم نفعل ذلك بالفعل...؟
Enjoy your meal.
أتمنى لك وجبة شهية.
Originally, you only needed to do hard labor in the Sunken Abyss.
في الأصل، كنت تحتاج فقط إلى القيام بأعمال شاقة في الهاوية الغارقة.
It was Ji Bozai who exposed everything.
لقد كان جي بوزاي هو من كشف كل شيء.
Now, the Sunken Abyss has been sealed,
الآن، تم إغلاق الهاوية الغارقة،
and the Judgment Hall has released you.
وقد أطلق سراحك قاعة الحكم.
Even if you know little,
حتى لو كنت تعرف القليل،
you might
ربما انت
accidentally reveal a secret.
كشف سر عن طريق الخطأ.
So we have no choice
لذلك ليس لدينا خيار
but to turn you into feed.
ولكن لتحويلك إلى علف.
Lord Hanfeng.
اللورد هانفنغ.
Don't blame me.
لا تلومني.
If you want to blame someone, blame Ji Bozai.
إذا كنت تريد إلقاء اللوم على شخص ما، ألقي اللوم على جي بوزاي.
So weak.
ضعيف جداً.
Pathetically weak.
ضعيف بشكل مثير للشفقة.
One twist and you'd snap.
لفة واحدة وسوف تنكسر.
How will you
كيف سوف تفعل ذلك؟
survive like this?
البقاء على قيد الحياة مثل هذا؟
I'm not weak.
أنا لست ضعيفا.
I... I even recovered from my Withered-Branch Disease.
أنا... حتى أنني تعافيت من مرض الأغصان الذابل.
I'm tougher than I look.
أنا أقوى مما أبدو.
I'll live
سأعيش
and grow into a towering tree.
وتنمو لتصبح شجرة شاهقة.
So
لذا
you want to be strong too.
تريد أن تكون قوياً أيضاً.
I... I was finally saved
أنا... لقد تم إنقاذي أخيرًا
after so much suffering.
بعد كل هذا المعاناة.
I can't let Mother down.
لا أستطيع أن أخذل أمي.
I can't waste the effort of those who saved me.
لا أستطيع أن أضيع جهد أولئك الذين أنقذوني.
I must live on.
يجب أن أستمر في العيش.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Let me help you.
دعني أساعدك.
Someone as weak as you
شخص ضعيف مثلك
can never become strong on your own.
لا يمكن أن تصبح قويًا بمفردك أبدًا.
Better to take another path:
من الأفضل أن تأخذ طريقا آخر:
become part of someone stronger.
تصبح جزءًا من شخص أقوى.
Perhaps
ربما
that's a blessing in disguise.
إنها نعمة مقنعة.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I took the Moonshade Grass.
لقد أخذت عشبة ظل القمر.
It cured my Withered-Branch Disease.
لقد شفى من مرض ذبول الأغصان.
So
لذا
I want to give this to you as a gift,
أريد أن أقدم لك هذا كهدية.
Immortal Ji.
الناس الخالدون.
My mother gave me this life.
لقد منحتني أمي هذه الحياة.
I must live it well.
يجب أن أعيشها بشكل جيد.
Thank you, Immortal Ji.
شكرا لك، جي الخالد.
Your Lordship!
سيادتكم!
♪Maybe I'm just your firefly♪
♪ربما أنا مجرد يراعة لك♪
♪That's why I'm so fragile♪
♪لهذا السبب أنا هش للغاية♪
♪In this world, there's too much♪
♪في هذا العالم، هناك الكثير♪
♪Cause and effect of love and hate surging♪
♪السبب والنتيجة لارتفاع الحب والكراهية♪
♪Would you be willing to stay for me?♪
♪هل أنت على استعداد للبقاء من أجلي؟♪
♪If your night is cold, with no warmth of the sun...♪
♪إذا كانت ليلتك باردة، ولا يوجد بها دفء الشمس...♪
So that's what it means
إذن هذا ما يعنيه
to form a heart imprint as a couple.
لتشكيل بصمة قلب كزوجين.
To share joy
لمشاركة الفرح
and suffering,
والمعاناة،
and to see what the other sees
ورؤية ما يراه الآخر
and feel what the other feels
وأشعر بما يشعر به الآخر
in their deepest pain.
في أعمق آلامهم.
♪If your world was once an endless wasteland♪
♪إذا كان عالمك ذات يوم أرضًا قاحلة لا نهاية لها♪
♪I'd tear myself apart to fill the wounds inside you♪
♪سأمزق نفسي لملء الجروح بداخلك♪
♪Even if this life is like a shooting star♪
♪حتى لو كانت هذه الحياة مثل نجم ساقط♪
♪Brief only for the sake of meeting you♪
♪مختصر فقط من أجل مقابلتك♪
♪In this fleeting life, I'll still be your light♪
♪في هذه الحياة العابرة، سأظل نورك♪
♪May this life be as fleeting as a firefly's glow♪
♪أتمنى أن تكون هذه الحياة عابرة مثل وهج اليراعة♪
♪Yet love may once again find its way back through time♪
♪ومع ذلك قد يجد الحب طريقه مرة أخرى عبر الزمن♪
♪Look, beneath the dark clouds♪
♪انظر، تحت السحب المظلمة♪
♪The fireflies fill the night sky♪
♪اليراعات تملأ سماء الليل♪
♪That's me. Do you remember?♪
♪هذا أنا. هل تتذكر؟♪
♪If your night is cold, with no warmth of the sun...♪
♪إذا كانت ليلتك باردة، ولا يوجد بها دفء الشمس...♪
Ji Bozai.
جي بوزاي.
♪Even in this restless world♪
♪حتى في هذا العالم المضطرب♪
♪My faint light♪
♪ضوئي الخافت♪
♪Will shine through for your brilliance♪
♪سوف تتألق من خلال تألقك♪
♪If your world was once an endless wasteland♪
♪إذا كان عالمك ذات يوم أرضًا قاحلة لا نهاية لها♪
♪I'd tear myself apart to fill the wounds inside you♪
♪سأمزق نفسي لملء الجروح بداخلك♪
♪Even if this life is like a shooting star♪
♪حتى لو كانت هذه الحياة مثل نجم ساقط♪
♪Brief only for the sake of meeting you♪
♪مختصر فقط من أجل مقابلتك♪
♪In this fleeting life♪
♪في هذه الحياة العابرة♪
♪I'll still be your light♪
♪سأظل نورك♪
♪When the drifting clouds♪
♪عندما تتحرك السحب♪
♪Flow toward me♪
♪تدفق نحوي♪
♪They drench my very soul♪
♪إنهم يغرقون روحي♪
♪Until it turns weak♪
♪حتى يصبح ضعيفًا♪
♪I deceive myself into thinking that to love once♪
♪أخدع نفسي بالاعتقاد بأن الحب مرة واحدة♪
♪Is enough♪
♪يكفي♪
♪Even if no true vow has ever been given♪
♪حتى لو لم يتم تقديم أي نذر حقيقي على الإطلاق♪
♪From the stars, how long must my tears travel to reach your heart?♪
♪من النجوم، كم من الوقت يجب أن تسافر دموعي لتصل إلى قلبك؟♪
♪The tenderness you give me is but love's poisonous wine♪
♪الحنان الذي تمنحني إياه ليس إلا نبيذ الحب السام♪
♪I drink down all of my sorrow♪
♪أشرب كل حزني♪
♪To trade for your freedom♪
♪للتجارة من أجل حريتك♪
♪Once I've tasted love, I long to be lost in its wine♪
♪بمجرد أن ذاقت الحب، أتوق إلى الضياع في نبيذه♪
♪After long struggles in the abyss, I ask the heavens♪
♪بعد صراع طويل في الهاوية، أطلب من السماء♪
♪Even if my armor shatters for you, what does it matter?♪
♪حتى لو تحطم درعي من أجلك، فما الذي يهم؟♪
♪Fate is never wrong♪
♪القدر لا يخطئ أبدًا♪
♪Even the sun must one day fall♪
♪حتى الشمس يجب أن تغرب يومًا ما♪
♪Against the world's absurdity, I fight with all my might♪
♪أحارب بكل قوتي ضد عبث العالم♪
♪From the stars, how long must my tears travel to reach your heart?♪
♪من النجوم، كم من الوقت يجب أن تسافر دموعي لتصل إلى قلبك؟♪
♪The tenderness you give me is but love's poisonous wine♪
♪الحنان الذي تمنحني إياه ليس إلا نبيذ الحب السام♪
♪I drink down all of my sorrow♪
♪أشرب كل حزني♪
♪To trade for your freedom♪
♪للتجارة من أجل حريتك♪
♪Once I've tasted love, I long to be lost in its wine♪
♪بمجرد أن ذاقت الحب، أتوق إلى الضياع في نبيذه♪